all right no idea how this is gonna go
because I've never been live on YouTube
before my guess is nobody will join
because I have like more subscribers to
my channel that's kind of what I'm going
for
not I would love more subscribers and
especially people who want to change the
world and want to cooperate and create a
stain efficient world together but also
I'm totally down with putting it out
there you know it's incomplete imperfect
for Matt and myself as well well finding
those people and like I don't think I
meant to go viral I think that somebody
else would come on board who can explain
it better
my mom just did this little cartoon
video for her business and she's you
know 25 years older than me she can
manage to do that I feel like I should
maybe be able to to put together a
little video like that so I'm going to
do which means figurine oh I don't know
part of me can i tweet to save the world
like president Trump just kind of does
it to like destroy the world so I think
I can do it together world course he has
like millions of followers but figuring
out how how to get this idea out there
and just talking about it and existing
there's a Facebook group one of my
friends as part of its it's like this
what is it called like the man who has
it all or something like that
and he kind of tweets it does Facebook
post in a world where the male/female
roles superber so it's like you know
what was he asking for it and what was
he wearing and and oh yeah I know he's
really good for like am an author and
like that that type of thing and I feel
like I've been called for a while to
kind of do that for this project in a
way like responding to events that
already like are happening in the real
world but like we'd created this better
world or we have this online way to
collaborate easily and efficiently
so let's try that right now so there was
just a post I saw this morning of all
names escape me who held the plane at a
European Airport so that a man from
Afghanistan wasn't deported back to
Afghanistan
otherwise I'm freaking thirsty and
therefore was actually my daughter and
it was amazing this woman's a hero my
kid wants to be a hero and I very much
encourage that of course you can be a
superhero you know what this person is a
superhero like oh no she's not
superpower sort of like no she has
privilege so we got into the
conversation of privilege and hand hi
why our skin gives us privilege and also
she's like what do you mean people with
darker skin don't have to stay out of
the Sun yeah that's biological privilege
that's different
I love five-year-old answers now we
can't go to the states anymore but in a
world where like that type of because
the truth is I don't even know might
used it did equal right up to now even
if you're a peaceful tribe if you're a
peaceful community someone who isn't
peaceful and has weapons can come and
destroy you now we have weapons that are
capable to destroyed all of humanity and
might no longer equals right it still
does he still loves total weird power
because you have any killer weapons and
such but if we organize the kind ones
the cooperative ones the the ones that
want to do good I can't believe everyone
wasn't standing up when I'm playing
first of all like a lot of the railing
at her she was understandably saying
back to them like I'm sorry you're gonna
be late for whatever you have plans on
the other end maybe you're
once-in-a-lifetime vacation this person
might will probably die if they go back
to Afghanistan
so yeah I'm okay with holding up this
light and they both ended up at the end
getting take it off oh she was like the
pilot has the right to refuse to fly
with anyone on board so the pilot can
say it can kind of like Trump who's
destroyed that we're forever the the law
like the deportation officers that are
gonna deport it now he might be put on
the next plane and there's no one in
that plane that's gonna stop him for me
and ported but what if there was what if
the next person like if we could
coordinate those efforts one they're
either gonna have to get private planes
that go the the other one show her was
remember the gender of the person who
standing up on the bus and saying like
no you we don't have to give our cards
dice the ice agents this is not their
jurisdiction you don't have to show them
and because she has the privilege of
being a legal US citizen and I think
they were also white got to use their
privilege to stop someone who might have
been deported because they're they don't
have documentation and so the more we
can do those things and I get that those
even if those people are few and far
between and I actually don't think they
are I think they're the majority and yet
the media and our powered psyches work
we kind of give more boys and more
screen time to the negative side I'd
like the racists and all and all of that
and people who are scared and doing and
right somewhat rightfully so like angry
racist rants should go viral and those
people shouldn't somewhat be ostracized
but I don't think it helps either the
people who are like it's not helping and
it keeps happening and it's like the
people are like the second jesse maybe I
shouldn't have a racist rants and so it
just really perpetuates because then
everyone gets to hear their racist rant
and yes they get ostracized but I don't
think that's not actually gonna help
them in any way be less racist and I
don't think it's helping people others
and it is helping the world know people
go through it having a world where we
can easily coordinate means that oh my
god that's awesome we all need to do
that we all need
to stand up on planes than Paris when
there's people being deported and if it
was seriously as easy as someone being
like I'm being deported right now on the
plane you know and it doesn't the truth
is it doesn't take a majority they don't
ask for an election and like who thinks
this person should say it's already been
through the courts he stole from people
does it mean he deserves to die like you
have tried them and put them in jail or
let them live the sentence did someone
to death or something like that is
ridiculous
abandon YouTube life which is great it's
kind of what I'm going for for 10
minutes today you're welcome and then
when it happens to be gold and happens
to be something that I'm like oh I
explained that really well then I'll
share it yeah what was the worksheet I
call her stubborn and she's stupid no it
doesn't and she's like well the you're
stubborn dude like yeah clearly you get
it from me anyway like adorable them not
understanding the world but like being
so passionate and adamant about
everything she does to not be called
stubborn I'm like I don't know what to
call you I can't watch shows 8 o'clock
sweetie my bedtime snotty a glass that's
not how that works but I'm very much
raising an egalitarian child of the
flank i you don't need to trust me just
because I'm the authority in your life
exactly it's weird because I all I do is
tell her the truth like that's why we
have a conversation about privilege and
skin this morning should constantly be
like really real because I guess I am
sarcastic and silly sometimes and she'll
be like real perio
then she kind of believes me but also
thinks I'm like never
I don't lie to you you asked me to tell
you the truth I tell you the truth even
when I don't want to tell you the truth
it's like where do these candy bar
wrappers come from how gross is bed last
night very somewhere I don't know I mean
we have understandably
my kids I was raised with Santa Claus
not being part of Christmas because I
was raised evangelical Christian it was
holiday so we never believed in Santa
Claus and I although I'm not a Christian
I there was something weird about lying
to your kid about Santa you can win
they're like are you sure it's real
you're like yeah of course man comes
down the chimney gives your presents
gives you more presents or less presents
than kids down the street with more or
less money ha ha ha anyway
so when I had her I was you know like my
parent not like my parents merging from
evangelical Christian but like oh it's a
story and it's a fun no she was having
none of that
Santa Claus is real I don't know who
you're talking about but if she asks I
am honest anyway so she had surgery done
on her mouth last year right pretty
close to Christmas in December and I
mean it was coming out of anesthesia
again under anesthesia to have it done
it was open like three hours even though
like when she's not in that state she
still believed in Santa it was like no
honey I didn't lie to you like you know
what he believes it and it's like the
fairy garden we have a fairy garden a
room and it used to be if she was asleep
I not in her room was cleaned it very
would leave her present Bank of like
gifts in my room the fairies go and take
and put them in there oh yeah kind of
like it's like plain and said like
magical childhood but not having that
trust issue of lying to your kid about
it it's like I don't believe but that
doesn't mean they're not real like you
might see them you might have them be
real
just cuz you're a kid and kids see
different things who am I to say you
don't one of my friends has the story
when her boys the boys are not like when
they were really little but twin boys
and they had a cat and the cat died and
they were like two at the time and came
home I went to give the dog treats like
they always do it
cat treats and she's like remember and
buddy but he died you know like if you
have one kid we see something you can
you know like argue it out of existence
but when you have two and they were
agreeing with each other it's like oh no
that's they can see the cat they it's
their kid I know I'd Access's I'm stuck
when I was a kid on my Mac this dinner I
just choose to believe we don't believe
we don't know a lot of in this world and
yet very scientific I'm very spiritual
and I'm using all of my weird
amalgamation of my individual quirks and
talents baby likes and dislikes to save
the world and it's not that everyone has
to get on board with what I believe and
what I the beauty is you absolutely
don't like we're gonna create a world
for the cooperative people and that's
where mite stops equal equally right cuz
now when one person stands up it's
easier for other people to stand up like
protests I think have more people out
there than usual and we can line stream
them and like media coverage doesn't
come but we we can record it and we can
share the news and we can share we can
do it
all easily by allowing people to do it
you just need to coordinate them like
okay someone who like if you record a
live video and you don't have but I
don't know whether that woman on the
plane because you can see on that like
this person commented it won been in
this is two minutes and 30 seconds
whether it was actually those people
commenting well she was live or whether
it's people commenting with her watch it
later cuz I don't know she would have
had to have that many followers like if
it was me who do live no one's coming on
to see that but then it could go viral
after and then people comments and stuff
right like anyway that you need to have
a certain number of followers before you
can kind of do those things just so that
there are people witnessing slide 30 are
apps for this but having it so that you
don't need to have that you just need
the app on the phone then it goes
directly to like you don't need to have
people watching cuz cuz everyone's gonna
be watching when it comes
people who are gonna watch it I care
about knowledge I care about science
they care about the truth it's something
that's like it's a fundamental core of
my being it's one of my I don't know
it's something that goes through my head
consoling like I don't know I don't know
I don't know and so therefore I have to
know I have to know except where I can't
know because I don't even know the steps
know it or I'm not able to learn it but
because I've had that as a driving force
to cover that up I've learned to
hell of a lot and you know like I've
always felt deficient in every area that
I know based on like oh I don't know
geography well have you seen people be
interviewed nobody knows geography and I
don't geography like I might not be able
to point it out exactly on a map I
probably know around where it is except
where things go right and same with like
history I'm not a historian but like I
understand what happened in world war
two I understand like the basics of our
recent history more so than your average
person but not as much as like my dad or
someone who's letting in to that
commitment and so and understands way
more going back of like all right well
here's the internship times anyway
having that need and then going to
university as a older than it's still a
young kid like you know I was like 21
when I went to murrs be having
understanding that even going to
university even doing a degree you know
so little about the subject that you
actually did a degree on you have to go
onto a masters and a PhD and even then
you know a tiny fraction of what is
knowable in that field and knowing like
truly like you're never gonna know
everything you can't it's not enough
hours in a day
not enough but I want access to all
about information I want to be able to
when I want to want to look something up
it's super easy and I can know if I
trust it is it just someone like
something we say all the time what is
that there's things that like appeared
in a movie a fictional movie and we now
treat them as the treatment is the truth
because it's just like well-known and
become like public figures how'd that
happen all inside especially like
historical ones like George Washington
and stuff definitely stopped to do with
Columbus that he thought he was going to
India or something when that wasn't I
don't think the case trying to get to
the world like there's common knowledge
that becomes so common knowledge that it
just Trump's the fact that it's not true
and to be able to look those things up
would be great I want history that I
care about which is not it's like I want
to know what life was like for my
ancestors I want to know which means not
the king and queen humping glint I want
to know what life was like for like the
Scots and the Irish and the Cherokee
people when like to able to trace my
lineage and see but not necessarily my
stories but like people who were in the
same class and the old to track our
genetics and see you know full human
human story and all those things like we
don't need everything to be great some
point five billion people get their
genomes done we do have so much
information but I get that not
everyone's gonna want to do that so the
more like the might equals right used to
be the case and now it's like the
cooperative people are gonna win and the
people who want to do good are gonna win
it's so weird cuz I talk to all of these
people about this idea like what about
people who are lazy and what about they
don't wanna continue what about people
if there's no money as an incentive and
they're not gonna do anything I'm like
yeah some people some people will only
be incentivized by money but most people
aren't incentivized by money if they're
incentivized by money it's not money
they're incentivized by its by the thing
that money represents so why not instead
just incentivize them with that like it
all right you want prestige you want to
know that you want people to know that
you invented it it'll probably do that
if that's the thing that's important
people you want to invent something to
not be known for it we can probably do
that too so that introverts can you like
or whatever people don't want their
names out there can feel like they can
also invent together their product out
there without their name out there that
because motivation like scientists don't
do science for money not the good ones
anyway they do it because they want that
they want to learn what they're studying
they want to figure out the answer to
this question people invent stuff
because they're like oh this is meeting
my need yes they'd also do it for money
but I don't think that money factor
helps us I think it hinders us because
it means that if I get something if I
invent something and I want all of the I
take all the risk and I get all the
profit and like yeah okay that systems
not nice to where we are it's had some
innovation but there's so many barriers
there it's like okay I have to not only
have a good idea I have to know how to
market it I have to know how to keep it
in the world I have to know how to do
all those things in order for people
just have access to it well it might not
be the idea that sucks I might just be
me that's like I might just not be the
person to put it out in the world and as
someone who's really stuck you putting
things out in the world I'm one of those
people but I have ideas and I know so
many people who have ideas and have
ideas but don't know how to promote the
world and they just don't and having no
like having access to information is
usable allowing people to geek out and
do what they love with people they love
and having the systems in place to help
them do that no matter what their skill
level and interests are that if you want
to play soccer at like two o'clock on a
Saturday you can probably find someone
in your city who wants to play soccer
two o'clock on a Tuesday if you want to
have an ongoing soccer game you can have
that if you want to have like a one-time
thing like if we organize it it's very
easy to find like I go on periscope and
I'm just like lost on that I'm like this
would be really cool you know isn't
because it's all like I've just scrolled
through all the people trying to solve
sex who try to buy sex and all the
people try to sell like leggings and
people trying to preach to each other
and then just all the like boring
which is totally fine though those ones
are more like okay I got this is kind of
or I'd be okay going through like okay
this person's just watching TV and this
person's painting and this person
singing songs miss person in order to
find the ones that are more having
intellectual conversations that I would
totally follow and enjoy watching but
instead it's like finding those ones in
the needle in the haystack of like all
of the like sex and everything else like
oh this is ridiculous like I know want
to be on here and so I go on periscope
but I don't necessarily watch other
people on periscope and anyway I'm gonna
quit this and why she's gonna go on
periscope
this one's 20 minutes and I said I don't
want you them for 10 minutes and when I
came on I did my first live video back
do you need more now that I know that I
can't do a live video we'll see how that
goes I will try to do a little more for
that kind of like I did yesterday but it
wasn't a live video like okay here's
what I want to talk about today to do
with the project do with my parents do
it whatever I feel like talking about at
the moment but hopefully kind of sort of
keeping my a TD brain on on topic
hopefully the idea is if this does get
bigger I might even do an hour a day
where people are actually participating
because then I can I think you like the
board meeting right let's move this this
project forward
take care I will see all of you slash
none of you tomorrow